uaex.edu 2019-06-01

# Privacy Policy | Arkansas Cooperative Extension

Thank you for visiting the University of Arkansas Division of Agriculture website and reviewing our privacy statement. The organization has a firm commitment to protecting your privacy. Information may be collected in the following ways: 

**Online web applications** \- Personal information concerning name, address, phone and e-mail may be requested by certain applications. The information you provide will be used only for the purposes of delivering the recommendations from the applications and notifying you of new versions, corrections or other information related to the recommendations. 

**Statistical logging** \- Automated logging of statistics related to the visitors to our website are kept strictly to analyze traffic on the website to assist in the efficient management and evolution of the material. This information will not be used for marketing or other non-related activities. 

**Cookies** \- A cookie file contains unique information that a website can use to track passwords, pages visited and the date visited, and to identify your session at a particular website. The only cookies in use on our site are for Google Analytics. Google Analytics is a web analytics tool that helps website owners understand how visitors engage with their website. Google Analytics customers can view a variety of reports about how visitors interact with their website so that they can improve it. 

We may collect information about your computer, including your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and in order to create reports. This is statistical data about our users’ browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual. 

Like many services, Google Analytics uses first-party cookies to track visitor interactions as in our case, where they are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We then use the information to compile reports and to help us improve our site. 

Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer’s hard drive. These cookies are used to store information, such as the time that the current visit occurred, whether the visitor has been to the site before and what site referred the visitor to the web page. 

Google Analytics collects information anonymously. It reports website trends without identifying individual visitors. You can opt out of Google Analytics without affecting how you visit our site – for more information on opting out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites you use, visit this Google page. 

**E-mail** \- Personal information collected via e-mail or through other online means will be used only for purposes necessary to serve your needs, such as responding to an inquiry for information. This may involve redirecting your inquiry or comment to another person or department better suited to meeting your needs. 

**Credit Cards -  **We work to protect the security of your information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input.  We reveal only the last four digits of your credit card numbers when confirming an order.  It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when finished using a shared computer. 

**_NOTICE OF YOUR PRIVACY RIGHTS UNDER THE EUROPEAN UNION’S GENERAL DATA PROTECTION REGULATION_**

To comply with the GDPR, the Division makes the following disclosures to you.

  1. The “data controller,” as defined by the GDPR, is the University of Arkansas Division of Agriculture (the Division). 
  2. Your personal data may be used by the Division to provide educational services and related goods and services to you. For example, we may store or process information you provide when you register for an online class or when you apply for or participate in Division programs or activities.  Your personal data will also be used to perform related administrative, regulatory and financial functions of the Division.  If you make purchases, such as instructional materials, we may process your personal data in order to complete transactions or provide the materials to you, and we may provide personal data to vendors, to the extent required by the Division’s agreements with such vendors. 
  3. Your personal data may also be processed by the Division in order to comply with legal obligations of the Division. These obligations may be imposed by United States federal law, the law of one of the United States, the law of the EU, or the law of an EU member state. 
  4. Your personal data may be processed in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interest of another person when you are incapable of giving consent, for reasons of public interest in the area of public health, for the purpose of protecting student health or safety, for the purpose of fulfilling legal obligations imposed upon the Division or when you have consented to the processing of your personal data. Personal data to be processed may include sensitive personal data, which the GDPR defines as information about racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, genetic data, biometric data for the purpose of identifying a person and data concerning health, sex life or sexual orientation. 
  5. Your personal data may be transmitted to, and stored in, facilities located in the United States of America, or in other facilities outside of the EU. 
  6. In order to provide goods or services to you, or to perform other functions described in this disclosure, your personal data may be viewed or processed by Division personnel. Your personal data may also be viewed or processed by contractors engaged by the Division to process data for the purposes described in this disclosure. 
  7. Your de-identified personal data may be used by the Division to assist the Division in assessing its programs and services, to provide information to assist the Division for administrative purposes, and for research purposes. 
  8. If you are an employee of the Division, your personal data may also be processed for purposes related to your employment. These uses include tax and regulatory reporting, creating and maintaining personnel, payroll and benefits records, and providing or administering employee benefits or employment-related insurance plans or products. 
  9. Your personal data will be stored until it is no longer required for the Division to accomplish the purposes described in this document. At a minimum, your personal data will be stored for the periods of time required by the Division’s legal obligations, including contractual obligations and obligations imposed by United States and Arkansas law. 
  10. Under the GDPR you have the right to access your personal data, to receive a copy of the personal data you provided the Division, and to have inaccurate personal data corrected.  You may also have the right to have your personal data erased when it is no longer needed for the purposes for which it was obtained. 
  11. Under the GDPR you may also have the right to restrict processing where: (a) you contest the accuracy of your personal data, (b) where the processing is unlawful and you request a restriction instead of erasure, and (c) where the Division must retain the data to establish or exercise the defense of a legal claim. 
  12. You may also have the right to restrict processing of your personal data: (a) if you contest the accuracy of your personal data; (b) if your personal data has been unlawfully processed and you request restriction of the data instead of erasure; (c) when the Division no longer needs your personal data for the purposes described in this disclosure, but is required to maintain your data in order to establish or defend a legal claim; and (d) when, pursuant to Article 21 of the GDPR, you have objected to processing your personal data. 
  13. Under Article 21 of the GDPR, you have the right to object to further processing of your personal data, on grounds specific to you, when the processing is not specific to your relationship to the Division but is for carrying out a task in the public interest or in the exercise of the Division’s official authority. 
  14. You have the right to object to use of your personal data for direct marketing purposes.
  15. Your personal data must be processed in order to administer your enrollment, to provide you with opportunities to attend classes or engage in field work or study-abroad programs, to purchase materials and to participate in Division programs.  The Division cannot provide you with educational or other goods or services, or the opportunity to engage in Division programs, without processing certain types of personal data described in this disclosure document. 
  16. To exercise your right to correction or erasure of your personal data, to request a copy of your personal data, or revoke any consent you have given, you must make your request, preferably in writing, to:  
Sam Boyster 

Chief Operating Officer

2301 S University Ave Little Rock AR 72204-4940  
501-671-2014, [sboyster@uaex.edu](mailto:sboyster@uaex.edu?subject=).
